A Guide to the Records of the Women's Club of Waycroft, 1960-1989
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Records of the Women's Club of Waycroft, 1960-1989
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 50
2 boxes.
Women's Club of Waycroft
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of A. M. (Peggy) Hughs in 1990.
Historical Information
Waycroft is a neighborhood in north Arlington, Virginia. The neighborhood is frequently paired with Woodlawn to form Waycroft-Woodlawn and stretches south and east from Virginia Hospital Center to Glebe Road and I-66. The Women's Club of Waycroft was organized in 1940 with the purpose of uniting community women in promoting the advancement of the civic and social welfare and the objectives of the Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs. The club was a member of the General Federation of Women's Clubs until disbanding in the 1990s.
Scope and Content
RG 50 houses the scattered records of the Women's Club of Waycroft, dating 1942 to 1989, with the bulk of material from 1960-1962 and 1981-1989. The record group measures .63 linear feet.
The records document the activities of the club, which include meetings with speakers on matters of civic interest and money-raising activities to benefit charitable organizations. Types of material include the club constitution, minutes, newsletters (The Whistle) and yearbooks, photographs and clippings. Series 2, Agendas, Minutes and Reports of Executive and Regular Meetings, have more detailed records for the 1981-1989 section, including treasurer's reports. There are only two images in Series 5, Photographs and Clippings.
Arrangement
RG 50 is divided into five series by type of material. Within the series, arrangement is chiefly chronological.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The Waycroft Women's Club was a member of the Federation of Women's Clubs. RG 16, Records of the Arlington County Federation of Women's Clubs, has more material about this group. There are also several folders of material from the Waycroft-Woodlawn Civic Association in RG 15, Records of Neighborhood Civic Associations.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Women in community organization; Women -- United States -- Societies and clubs.; Neighborhoods -- United States.; Citizens' associations; Waycroft (Arlington, Va.); Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Constitution, By-Laws, and History
  - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 1)
  - History of the Women's Club of Waycroft (Box 1)
  - Mary Stewart's Collect, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
  - Membership Applications, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
- Agendas, Minutes and Reports of Executive and Regular Meetings
  - Program Report, March 1942 (Box 1)
  - Membership Report, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Agendas and Minutes of Executive Committee Meetings, September 1960 - May 1961 (Box 1)
  - Agendas and Minutes of Regular Meetings, June 1960 - May 1961 (Box 1)
  - Reports of Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Agendas and Minutes of Executive Committee Meetings, September 1961 - May 1962 (Box 1)
  - Agendas and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1961 - May 1962 (Box 1)
  - Report on Meeting of Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs, October 1964 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1981 - May 1982 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1981 - June 1982 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, October 1981 - May 1982 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1982 - May 1983 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1982 - June 1983 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, August 1982 - April 1983 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1983 - May 1984 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1983 - June 1984 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, September 1983 - May 1984 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1984 - May 1985 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1984 - May 1985 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, September 1984 - June 1985 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1985 - May 1986 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1985 - June 1986 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, September 1985 - June 1986 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1986 - May 1987 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1986 - June 1987 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, September 1986 - June 1987 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1987 - May 1988 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1987 - June 1988 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, September 1987 - June 1988 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Executive Board Meetings, September 1988 - May 1989 (Box 1)
  - Attendance and Minutes of Regular Meetings, September 1988 - May 1989 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, September 1988 - February 1989 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1955, 1961, 1972 (Box 1)
- Publications
  - Waycroft Whistle, 1958, 1960, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Waycroft Whistle, September 1961 - May 1962 (Box 1)
  - The Whistle, September 1981 - April 1982 (Box 1)
  - The Whistle, October 1985 - May 1986 (Box 1)
  - The Whistle, September 1986 - May 1987 (Box 1)
  - The Whistle, September 1987 - May 1988 (Box 1)
  - The Whistle, September 1988 - May 1989 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1941/1942 - 1963/1964 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1964/1965 - 1977/1978 (Box 2)
  - Yearbooks, 1978/1979 - 1981/1982 (Box 2)
- Photographs and Clippings
  - Photographs, 1961, n.d. (Box 1)
  - 1950, 1961-1962 (Box 1)